# JIMMY NGUYEN

# React Frontend Developer

Milwaukee, WI (262) 957-6232 Nguyen89.MKE@gmail.com LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Next.js, React, React Hook Forms, MongoDB, Node, JavaScript, RESTful APIs, HTML/CSS, GitHub

#### SUMMARY

I was a **Full Cycle Recruiter** for 5 years before transitioning into a **freelance web developer** creating **Full Stack Applications** with the **MERN** tech stack.

Currently, I am a salaried **React Frontend Developer**. The skills I have developed in the Human Resources and Software Development field have allowed me to become a well rounded professional in both soft and technical skills.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# React Frontend Developer | GCOM Partners | Milwaukee, WI

March 2023 - Current

- Technologies: Next 13, Chakra UI, React Hook Forms, React, JavaScript, Storybook
- Solo Frontend Developer tasked with creating all visual components
- Coaching and Mentoring junior developers on the fundamentals of react and functional components.
- Created an entire frontend web application using reusable functional components within a steep time crunch resulting in high client satisfaction by means of contract extension.

### Freelance Web Developer | Remote

August 2022 - March 2023

Technologies: MongoDb, Express, React, Node

- Created portfolios and gaming resources pages which helped students during the interview process and saved time for gamers.
- Lead a class on React and JavaScript fundamentals to help other career transitioners.

#### Talent Acquisition Specialist | Cielo | Brookfield, WI

June 2018 - May 2022

- Team Lead tasked with creating offer packages and processing onboarding tasks.
- Managed and handled Career Fairs, Recruitment Events, and Candidate Travel.
- Hosting and Evaluating Candidates In Interview Screenings
- Auditing high volume teams to manage candidate flow.
- Updating candidate profiles through various Applicant Tracking Systems (ATS)

# **EDUCATION**

# TECH I.S. | Web Development

Completed 2022 2016-2019

University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee | Human Resources

Full Stack Developer Certificate

Programming Foundations: Algorithms Certificate

Programming Foundations: Object-Oriented Design Certificate

### Personal Projects

# Full Stack Web Application | MERN - MongoDB, Express, React, Node | MMORPG Resource Website

Technologies: MongoDb, Express.js, React.js, Node.js

- Collaborated with other developers in the gaming community to put together a web application that provides information in a convenient area to speed up player progression.
- Fetching data and hosting it in a convenient and accessible location has increased progression speed by up to 45%. (Numbers compared during speed runs)
- Created as a free resource to support the community, it has received positive feedback and support. With plans to incorporate
  ideas from other members of the community, there will be more features implemented.

# Player Profile MOBA API

Technologies: MongoDb, Express.js, React.js, Node.js

- Using Riot Games' public API, this website searches for a given name and returns their player profile and details.
- When the page is rendered, the useEffect hook on mount sends a GET Request for the JSON data. Upon success, stores the JSON data to the state, then compares it to the given search string.
- The client sends CRUD requests to the server which then communicates to the MongoDb database.

#### 2D Fighting Game - Vanilla JS

- Created with Object Oriented Design and Programming fundamentals.
- Characters were created under a class with objects inheriting shared characteristics from it.
- Refactored the code using polymorphism and was able to remove Switch/Case or long If/Else statements.

#### **OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS**

# **Poker Leaderboard Application**

- The application showed hand statistics so players could study positions and would also store a player's history/achievements.
- Resolved state management bugs by upgrading to React which allowed us to use Redux for the updated state management.
- Made the application more accessible by other developers by introducing a new folder structure as the application grew.